Okay, we are not going to call to over the rigorous council meeting for today's date.
Item number two is proclamation declaring April 22, 2016 Judy Snorley Day, Judy Snorley.
As retiring after 29 years with maids and serving the community in this rounding area,
we're going to, and so April 22nd is the day that we're setting aside to honor her.
Item number three is a proclamation declaring April 25th through 28th of 2016 community crisis center volunteer appreciation week.
And there's also another group of people that we appreciate and that it serves the community in this rounding area for a long time.
So we want to recognize them with a proclamation.
Item number four is public input and unscheduled personal appearances.
If there anyone in the audience wishes to address the council on any of the agenda items.
You're being non item five is consent agenda staff is recommending item 6 through 17 be placed on the consent agenda.
If there are no questions of objections, I would entertain a motion.
Some of them are.
And second.
Second.
Doug seconded.
Paul council please.
Johnson.
Justin.
Aye.
Forster.
Hi.
Item 18 is a letter of interest to open home an aeronautic commission.
Tyler.
How are you today?
Good.
This is a letter of interest to the OIC for the cities in the running or for a $1.2 million grant.
And this grant will fix the lights on the runway.
They're currently down right now because they're direct berry.
So we'll be putting on new lighting system, new A-Wass system, which pilots used for the weather for the wind, directions, everything.
So it's a lot of improvements to the airport.
So of the $1.2 million grant, this would be responsible for approximately $110,000.
Okay.
So this is a competitive grant.
Yes, sir.
But is our understanding that we are the funds there?
The agenda.
Yeah.
The city sure is adding $2,000.
Okay.
Well that's.
Yes, but that's.
We have some money.
We have to pay like additional engineering for this year.
So.
We got to pay that regardless.
If we do the grant.
Okay.
Dean, are you.
Do you need further clarity or we've good to go?
I'd like to ask that you go ahead and improve this, but I would like to take another look at this.
Okay.
That's information that you were not provided.
And so what you're asking for Tyler is simply approval of course submission of the letter.
Yes, sir.
Of the letter of interest to the FA.
Okay.
Do we have a motion to approve this?
I'm going to approve.
Doug?
And second.
Can I ask a question first?
Is that when we know this?
We should hear back something pretty soon from the FA. They're very, they send us this stuff and we need it back within a short amount of time
Okay, and then we need and the time is up in this and that's why. Okay, it's important to do that. I'll try again.
Okay, so
Roll call please.
Western.
Hi.
Johnson.
Forster.
Sure.
Thank you.
Thank you Tyler.
Item 19's award bid C1664 for construction of trade improvements and a sunset strip from East Street to G Street Southwest.
And these concrete construction.
Authorities, the city manager and city attorney decide the notice to proceed. Once all retired documents are received.
Take Chuck.
Thank you.
Well, we advertise in the paper as required for bidding these projects out and held a pre-bid conference.
The low bidder was niece construction.
212,558 and 50 cents.
He submitted all the documents as required for the bid, which is listed in there.
The bid schedule, qualifications statement not collusion affidavit.
And city staff is recommending the award of this project in this concrete construction.
Okay, do we have a motion?
Motion to Primer.
Second.
Roll call.
Johnson.
All right.
Western.
Forster.
Sure.
All right.
And I.
19 is award of bid number 1665, which is also street improvements.
Excuse me.
Please, Southwest from Second Avenue, Southwest.
Steve Owens.
Also in these construction.
Go ahead, Chuck.
And just the same script as the last one, the regular advertisements.
And in this one, we're recommending the award to niece construction.
Okay.
I'll make a motion.
Can I ask one question?
Are these on some of the streets that will come into play this year?
Yes, this is this is going to be this was there on some of them.
Definitely this was part of the program that you've approved.
Okay.
Thank you.
But not only have you approved, but it's also gone through the planning commission.
I just want to make sure that those were the same ad.
Yes.
Now there's some additional ones coming up.
But these were two of them ones that were on that process.
When they originally.
Okay.
So I made a motion.
Do we have a second?
Second.
Roll call.
Shield.
Forster.
Fine.
Western.
Johnson.
New business.
Do you know anyone?
Not on this one.
Okay.
Staff reports.
Sorry.
In your packet.
American.
Can we go back to.
Automate team for a minute.
Yes.
Dean.
What would this money come out of?
We'll be able to budget a minute.
It will.
It will probably be a budget a minute.
In fact, one of the things we're looking at with the airport board is.
that normally these come out of their port funds, you know the airport generates revenue and they
do cover them costs. Now the airport has been down we'll be talking about this in budget when
we talk about budget. The airport has been down quite a bit this year. They've just changed over
to a new fixed-based operator and there has not been a lot of fuel sales there because fuel
pumps were down. We just have changed those to a new self-service fuel pump. We think by them now
in the end of the fiscal year we should see those numbers go up. But if we do this we may take some
of the money out of our general fund first to kind of front it but then when airport revenue
start to increase when we start seeing more people have their planes at the airport we may take
that back from some of the airport items trying to keep the airport as a basically an enterprise
fund where it pays for itself. But again you know $100,000 for about $1.2 million is something
that we really need to do for the airport and also the light system we talk about the lights.
What these are our approach lights. These are safety items for the pilots to be able to know that
they're on the right approach to be able to land and take off and those types of upgrades. So if we're
going to be in the airport business we need to do this but yeah we may have to kind of front the money
but my goal and it's going to be the airport as always an enterprise fund and it pays for itself.
And that's the total amount when it will cost to make that happen. Yes.
It was 1.2 a division. Yeah and plus our one or two is the grand plus. Right we have to correct.
Where's the American staff record? Yes staff reports in the packets. We're having questions for staff.
Yes I have one for Chuck. You have some information for us.
Sooning you're talking about the animal shelter. Yes sir. Yes.
Today the contractor and construction services group dropped off their sign contracts. If the last
meeting you guys approved, getting the notice of a award, they've returned the sign documents today
along with their project schedule and anticipating that that will get through legal and
and issue the notice proceed here shortly. They've submitted a schedule. Next week they're planning
on being on site, start marking the site, moving their trailer in and getting their anxious to get
going on this project. So what do you need from David? Now it's the last meeting we awarded the project
and once they submitted all their proper documentation that the city attorney and city manager
would issue the notice proceed. So we just got those documents back today from them. So it's all
and it's already been authorized at the last meeting as long as their paperwork and their bonds and
everything which they submitted today, we just issued an notice proceed and tell them. So you don't
David doesn't need to review anything for you. Well again the award was subject to the attorney
and the city manager issuing the notice per se.
I think I understand if you were saying that we need to have a legal review of their
stuff or not.
No, that there was a lot of contracts that we submitted to them.
Okay.
All right.
We've already signed off on the contracts before Mayor.
Can't you do it?
Good deal.
Thank you, Chuck.
Any other questions for staff on anything in the packet?
If not mayor and council meeting announcements and announcements?
That's it.
Okay.
City manager communication.
Just one fun one tonight.
And that is that we put the news out yesterday that the job and blasters are going
to have their season opener at Joe Pollock Field on May 12th at 6 p.m., tickets are going
to be $5 and they're available here at City Hall.
Plus they're also available at the Coleman and available at Chamber of Commerce.
Talking to the blasters, they're trying to get a lot of people to be aware of that.
The fact that they're in the region, they're trying to get a lot of fan base going.
And since we have a really good, high to major league baseball in Mr. Mantle, thought that we'd
be very good and they appreciated it.
City of Joplin has worked great with us on this because they understand what we're trying to do as well.
And we've also had both NEO, the high school and RBI.
Helping us with us as well.
And of course, want to mention Amanda too.
She's done a great job during a time that she's very busy with things like the radio.
So I really appreciate the works she put in.
And we've been trying to bring it to my Emma.
When you say, take it to available here at City Hall, is that be it the utility office?
Yes, sir.
Great.
Well, I'm looking forward to that.
Any other city manager communications?
No, that's okay.
Item number 25 is the executive session for sure.
It's just 2050, S307, B1 and 307E.
Do we have a motion to go into executive session for the reasons listed in the agenda item 25?
I'll take a sentence as a session.
I'll take a motion.
Yes, sir.
We're all called, please.
Four, sir.
Hi.
Question?
Johnson.
Hi.
We're all just a being.
I'll just try to do that.
Are you ready, sir?
Okay.
We are out of the executive session at 16.
Item 26 on the agenda is the German.
Do we have a motion to adjourn?
Motion to adjourn?
And a second.
Second.
Question?
Aye.
Four, sir.
Shoulders.
Aye.
Could close another minute.
Oh, we got some.